Malcolm Eastman

Queens, NY | 718-926-6929

<u> Malcolmeastman.tech | Linkedin.com/in/malcolm-eastman</u>

Malcolm@malcolmeastman.tech

HOME LABS

Azure Home Lab

- Users and groups were configured and created within Azure AD.
- Conditional access policies are created and enforced to ensure certain conditions are met before a log in within Azure.
- Access reviews were created to make sure permissions are still in use and needed.
- Built Azure VMs and deployed them to various groups within Azure.
- Created resources groups.
- Created virtual networks within Azure to create secure connections between different Azure resources.
- Microsoft 365 tools were overseen within the Azure tenant to make sure users have all the resources necessary to complete their jobs.
- Azure compliance and security tools are utilized to keep all resources, devices and users safe and within compliance.
- Made and maintained Azure containers.

Juniper vLabs

- Constructed networks WLANS and LANS.
- Setup VLANS to separate devices on the same physical switch.
- Configured switches, routers, WAPS and security devices.
- Setup firewalls to direct and block traffic on managed switches and routers.
- Troubleshooted Juniper network devices.
- Explored the options and capabilities of juniper devices using the Junos OS.

Cisco Packet Tracer

- Configured Cisco routers, switches and WAPS.
- Built Cisco network topologies.
- Troubleshooted Cisco network devices.
- Created and managed network LANS and WLANS.
- Configured network firewalls on managed switches and routers using Cisco IOS.

AWS Home Lab

- Created and maintained active directories.
- Configured users, identities and access with IAM. (Identity and access management)
- Created Amazon S3 buckets for storage within Amazon S3.
- ,Made Amazon WorkSpaces so virtual desktops are available to users no matter the location.
- Constructed VM's, VPNs using AWS EC2.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a dedicated technology professional with a focus on networking and cloud computing. I have used my expertise in technology to create environments where efficiency is easily attainable. I find and create solutions that get the job done. My value goes beyond hard skills as my wide array of soft skills have also benefited multiple workplace environments.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Electronic/Appliance repair
- Staff Support
- Ticketing system management (Zoho Desk and Spiceworks)
- Communication/Customer Service
- Cloud Computing
- Coaching/Mentoring
- Technical Troubleshooting
- Computer Networking
- Microsoft Azure
- Amazon AWS
- End User Training

CERTIFICATIONS

- Comptia A+
- Comptia Network+
- Maker Bot Operator
- Juniper Networks Certified Associate, Junos (JNCIA-Junos)
- Smart Digital Certified Trainer
- Google IT Support Professional Certified
- Microsoft Certified: Identity and Access Administrator Associate
- Microsoft 365 Certified: Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified: Cybersecurity Architect Expert

Work Experience

Digital Skills Teacher/It Service Desk 02/2020 to Current Brooklyn Urban Garden Charter School - Brooklyn, NY

- · Answered and documented service tickets.
- Developed and co-managed a junior tech team.
- Taught tech enrichment and P.E classes.
- Provided technical support to students and staff.
- Maintained school endpoints.
- Troubleshoot with tech equipment such as mac books, chrome books, smart boards, Epson/Ricoh projectors and printers.
- Familiarized students with Google workspace and apple tools.
- Tracked student data with teacher ease and google sheets.
- Walked students through 3D modeling as well as printing using Tinkercad, MakerBot and Elegoo 3D printers.
- Educated students on how they can be a good digital citizen and what their digital footprint looks like.
- Served as a member of the school's tech team to address the school's technical needs.
- Provisioned laptops to students and staff for academic use.
- Conducted hardware repairs on endpoints.

Teaching Assistant/It Support, 02/2018 to 02/2020 SCO Family of Services - Queens, NY

- Troubleshoot with on premise endpoints.
- Supervised residents on residential units.
- Educated students and staff on how to maintain and repair endpoints.
- Developed structured work study program.
- Set up thin clients for use with on premise smart boards.
- Taught technology classes.
- Applied updates to endpoints.
- Served as the assistant basketball coach for school's team.
- Assisted lead teachers with lesson plan development.
- Provided technical support to staff and students.

Activity Specialist 09/2015 to 1/2020

YMCA - Queens, NY

- Enhanced age-appropriate growth and developmental skills.
- Facilitated basketball, baseball, track, tech and chess classes.
- Served as a coach and referee for the YMCA's basketball league.
- Worked through multiple departments with the goal of aiding student achievement.
- · Maintained child records.
- Developed and implemented themes and activities for children between ages of eight and eighteen.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Queensborough Community College

Queens, NY

Associates Degree, Liberal Arts and Sciences

Expected in 2023